
<Lesson stage="3" page="8" type="Reading Check">
<APageParagraph activityIntroClip="uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3"  pencil="p3" skipIntro="true">
   <paragraph>
       <sentence>
         <text>CR</text>
         <clip></clip>
      </sentence>  
      <sentence>
         <text>After the war with Mexico (1846-1848), the homestead movement got bigger.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>People who came to the States from Europe were ambitious to make a new life so moved west.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>When the South left the Union, a major stumbling block to homesteading was removed.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
   </paragraph>
   <paragraph>
       <sentence>
         <text>CR</text>
         <clip></clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>CR</text>
         <clip></clip>
      </sentence>   
      <sentence>
         <text>In 1862, the Homestead Act passed into law.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>The new law had three steps to owning land: filing a claim, improving the land, and filing for deed of title.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>Any U.S. citizen could apply and in exchange for improving the land and building a dwelling, the homesteader could file for the deed to own the land after 5 years.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
   </paragraph>
   <paragraph>
      <sentence>
         <text>Physical existence for the homesteader was very hard.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
       <sentence>
         <text>Crops were blown down by strong winds and blizzards in the winter.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	   </sentence>
	   <sentence>
		   <text>The summers were scorching and had swarms of insects.</text>
		   <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	   </sentence>
	   <sentence>
		   <text>Fuel and water supplies were short, so simple cooking and heating chores were hard.</text>
		   <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
       <sentence>
		   <text>The plots on the dry plains were too small to grow large crops.</text>
		   <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	   </sentence>
	   <sentence>
		   <text>The landscape made grazing livestock on the prairie difficult .</text>
		   <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	   </sentence>
	   <sentence>
		   <text>In many places, the experiment failed and the homesteader did not stay on the land long enough to make a final claim.</text>
		   <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
		   <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	   </sentence>
   </paragraph>
   <paragraph>
	   <sentence>
		   <text>CR</text>
		   <clip></clip>
	   </sentence>
	   <sentence>
         <text>However, homesteaders who toughed it out were rewarded with excellent chances for wealth and a new life.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>By 1934, over 1.6 million homestead claims had gone through the system and more than 270 million acres given over.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>In 1976 the Homestead Act was stopped in 48 states, but homesteading was allowed in Alaska until 1986.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>The state of Nebraska has the national memorial to the Homestead Act.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
   </paragraph>
</APageParagraph>
</Lesson>
