
<Lesson stage="3" page="9" type="Reading Check">
<APageParagraph activityIntroClip="uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3"  pencil="p3" skipIntro="true">
   <paragraph>
   	  <sentence>
		  <text>CR</text>
		  <clip></clip>
	  </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>The oil industry grew as a direct result of the motor car.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>More precisely, it was because of the internal combustion engine, which burns the gasoline made from oil.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>Oil is formed from the remains of plants and creatures living millions of years ago and the weight of tons of rock pressed on those remains. This caused a gradual change.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>      
       <sentence>
         <text>CR</text>
         <clip></clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>CR</text>
         <clip></clip>
      </sentence>  
      <sentence>
         <text>The liquid, which has been trapped and compressed under the weight of rock above it, rushes to the surface.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>To obtain the oil a gigantic drill works its way down from the surface and breaks into the lake of oil.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>The liquid, which has been trapped and compressed under the weight of the rock above it, rushes to the surface.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	  </sentence>
  </paragraph>
  <paragraph>
	  <sentence>
		  <text>There are two main problems for the oil industry.</text>
		  <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>First of all, scientists have to locate the oil-bearing rocks.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>Then, the oil engineers have to drill at exactly the right spot.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>Some drills have to drill into the ground as deep as four miles down before oil is found.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	  </sentence>
	  <sentence>
		  <text>When the oil is found, it has to be moved, often by pipeline.</text>
		  <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	  </sentence>
	  <sentence>
		  <text>Some pipelines are over 1,000 miles in length.</text>
		  <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	  </sentence>
	  <sentence>
		  <text>One of the largest pipelines in the world runs through Alaska.</text>
		  <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
   </paragraph>
   <paragraph>
       <sentence>
         <text>CR</text>
         <clip></clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>Second, we now know that the sources of crude oil will run dry.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
       <sentence>
         <text>Our way of life depends on oil.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>Large amounts of oil are used in industry, for fuel and to run cars.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>When the oil runs out we will need to replace it with things such as solar and nuclear power.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
      <sentence>
         <text>But each of these has its own drawbacks.</text>
         <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
	  </sentence>
	  <sentence>
		  <text>This means that finding a replacement for crude oil is a slow process.</text>
		  <clip>uk/assets/sound/whiteSpace.mp3</clip>
      </sentence>
   </paragraph>
</APageParagraph>
</Lesson>
